LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
I'm a soldier - that means I'm
Both a defendant and the judge
I am standing on both ends of the flame
Rounding curves
Overtaking life and death,
I run and fight with false shadows
No matter how many threads of deception are woven together,
The truth shall illuminate the face of light
Save your tears for the day
when our pain is far behind
on your feet, come with me
We are soldiers stand or die
Save your fears, take your place
Save them for the judgement day
fast and free, follow me
Time to make the sacrifice.
We rise or fall
Have you managed to dig up anything on him?
The outlook isn't very promising.
The information is under tighter control than I expected.
After all, the Intelligence Agency is the
newest administrative organisation to surface
after the pre-war intelligence agencies and
the former Bureau of Defence Policy merged.
However, as far as Gouda's Investigative Council for
Possible Changes to Wartime Strategy is concerned,
I've found evidence of illegal information
manipulation in their collection and analysis
of domestic and foreign intelligence and SDF activities.
So, the plutonium incident is only
one of the instances of manipulation?
That seems to be the case.
What about his personal history?
He was headhunted from the
Bureau of Defence Policy,
and then made a rapid ascent through
the ranks to his current position.
At the time, however, his performance was mediocre.
He seems to have been more of a failure.
He's an enigmatic man, to tell you the truth.
What is that?
Gouda's appearance during his years at the Bureau of Defence Policy.
He apparently got those wounds in some kind of accident,
but he's opted to keep the scars intact.
He wasn't as striking as he is now.
All right.
We'll halt the investigation on his background
for now while we wait for the Chief's orders.
Roger.
Good grief... Straight from an all-nighter
into a lunch meeting, eh?
A Vegetarian
Banquet
I have called this emergency session
to announce our future policy regarding
the series of events that has recently occurred.
Before we get into all that, I'd like to deck that guy first.
I agree.
The Intelligence Agency's actions are
clearly meant to put pressure on us.
I have no intention of backing down
after already facing that pressure twice.
Don't worry, I feel exactly the same way.
Even so, you seem to be making frequent
visits to the Prime Minister's office.
Isn't it the Prime Minister herself who wants to rein us in?
That seems unlikely.
It's true that she's just a figurehead
who was installed in order to divert
the public's attention away from the
bribery scandal of the previous regime.
However, while she may only occasionally act
as our ally, she will never become our foe.
I believe the Major is conducting her
own investigation into the matter.
As for the Cabinet Intelligence Agency, it appears
to have deliberately manipulated the information
regarding the GSDF helicopter incident and the
recent plutonium transportation incident.
Thus far, the Agency's intentions remain unclear,
but I believe that the pressure being repeatedly brought
to bear upon us is being exerted by political factions
within the government that wish to hide something from us.
Including the Individual Eleven case?
Yes.
After all, they are holding us back from investigating,
even though we were the ones most closely involved in
fending off the assassination attempt on the Prime Minister.
Even if we suppose that the
Prime Minister is a paper tiger,
if our opponent is the government, it won't change
the fact that we're biting the hand that feeds us.
But you'll still proceed, right?
You object to that?
No, that's what I was waiting to hear.
All right, then.
I will now explain our planned course of action.
Designated Major Wide-Area Case by the National Police Agency:
Case No. 104 The Individual Eleven Case
The information I've assembled here is from numerous cases
that were instigated by different organisations
claiming to be the Individual Eleven.
The JNN TV charity fund misappropriation case,
the bombing of the Refugee Support Association,
the blackmail of the NPO that was
providing refugees with free cybernetic bodies,
the death by drowning of a back-alley cybernetic body physician,
the vehicular killing of a netbank president,
the stabbing of a Civilian Party representative,
the shooting of the popular cyber-rapper, "Densetsu,"
the blackmail of Nanyou News Agency,
and the failed assassination attempt on Prime Minister Kayabuki.
Of these nine incidents,
the failed assassination attempt was assumed to be
the only one in which the suspect's face was seen,
but we now have another incident in
which the suspect's face was witnessed.
That's news to me.
Wasn't the National Police Agency resisting any disclosure?
Yes. Unlike in the Laughing Man Case,
they are quite serious about this one,
although it is also true that their
mindset is proving to be an obstacle for us.
This is footage we obtained directly
from a witness, not from the police.
As in, from a Nanyou reporter?
Correct.
Up to this point, Nanyou's premises have been
fired upon three times by the Individual Eleven
ostensibly as a result of Nanyou's
critical stance against refugee policies.
The man who was captured on security
camera footage in all three of these instances
is this man, Kawashima Shou.
He began working as a Taiwanese vegetarian chef
at a restaurant near the Nanyou News Agency about a month ago.
We've found records that he used to be an SDF officer as well.
Where did you find that information?
I sent data on the individual's facial structure to military
intelligence, and managed to gain their cooperation.
So in the end, we're more cosy with
the military than with the police.
Well? What do you want us to do about him?
First, secure this man.
Investigate the significance hidden in his
ideology and the connections behind him.
At this point in time, we haven't been
able to confirm whether any connection
exists between the Cabinet Intelligence
Agency and the Individual Eleven,
but if we try to unravel what medium resulted in
the emergence of a terrorist stand alone complex,
their intentions should become more transparent.
You may be right.
Batou, Togusa, Saitou and Pazu,
you four are to secure Kawashima Shou.
Ishikawa and Bomer, you two will
continue to investigate Gouda's background
and search for the whereabouts of the terrorist
who attempted to assassinate the Prime Minister.
Roger.
Nanyou News Agency
Things finally feel normal again, but I still don't get these people.
The Individual Eleven, eh...
The seven other cases don't seem similar,
besides that they all push for refugee liberation.
They don't have anything in common aside from
that symbol on their claims of responsibility, either.
If this case is the same as the Laughing Man case,
would it mean that the "originals" are the
terrorists who occupied the Chinese Embassy?
The were the first group to name
themselves the Individual Eleven, after all.
But no one else has called
themselves that, aside from them.
We only figured out how to interpret the symbol after
investigating it and tracing it back to that theorist's paper.
It just means that the individual who
provides the motivational medium
in a stand alone complex case is
not necessarily the "original", right?
That's true, but I feel that the guys who are using this
symbol are the ones who are being more original.
This tastes awful!
What the hell; these are for cyborgs!
Eh, you won't die from eating them.
Its composition is 90% gluten and a trace
amount of amino acid-based micro-machines.
Yo, how'd it go?
No luck.
He hasn't been back to his
apartment for at least four days.
I'll try staking out the newspaper agency instead.
All righty.
We're behind.
Even if we have some leads,
if they're not fresh, they're useless.
Now what, Major?
Should we continue with the stakeout?
As long as securing the suspect remains our top priority,
we have no choice but to continue.
After all, Nanyou continues to be threatened,
and he was showing up at the
restaurant right up until yesterday.
We're not being very proactive though, are we?
I've sent reinforcements to cover our numbers.
The stakeout won't become more efficient by
just sending three additional Tachikoma units.
Oh stop that, Togusa-kun.
We've become able to synchronise
while retaining individuality,
not to mention that we've now
acquired the agent function! Ta-dah!
In other words, it's like we can have
out-of-body experiences now!
Now we can gather intelligence
while our physical bodies stay on-site!
We're calling this the feast of information!
Enough with the chatter.
Batou, increase the IR system's search efficiency
and focus on securing Kawashima.
Roger.
Let's go!
When did the Major rig them up?
It's true that we've been short on manpower lately.
We're totally unable to find anything,
even though I think that if anyone attempted to get a
PKF-spec cybernetic body, there'd definitely be a trail...
Perhaps he's no longer in the country?
Makes us want to doubt the Intelligence
Agency's research, that's for sure.
Major, I found out something interesting from the local net.
It's the graduation thesis Gouda wrote as a student.
"Should Cyberbrains Respect Individuality or Cooperation in Society?
A Theory on Heroism from a Producer's Viewpoint"
It's surprisingly interesting.
As the title indicates,
the thesis points out how cyberbrains
tend to subconsciously desire cooperation
in the current social structure,
even as they lose their individuality.
It discusses how we might create a
leader who would leverage this information
to deliberately control the masses'
subconscious as part of the system.
Sounds like a structural analysis
of the Laughing Man Case.
Yeah.
But if you look at the date, it shows that he wrote
this a long time before the Laughing Man Case.
Gouda Kazundo
After he wrote the thesis, he went on to learn Information
Science, Information Ethics, and Applied Informatics,
and was employed in the private sector for a time.
In the private sector...?
A multinational corporation
whose name would be known to all
for its cybernetic technology
and micro-machine manufacture:
Poseidon Industrial.
At the time, it was known as Dai-Nippon Giken.
Go to Hakata via the super-expressway.
Understood.
It's me.
Aramaki. I'm sorry, but I won't be able
to spare as much time as I'd hoped.
When will you arrive?
The time I promised I'd be there by.
I see...
Then how about if we meet at that restaurant?
We shouldn't meet anywhere too public, after all...
That's fine with me.
I see.
Then I'll head there first.
Damn, that looks good.
I haven't been home at all lately, either.
Do you even know what that is?
Eels, right? Even I know that much.
Wrong.
That's a fake eel dish made from
gluten and shiitake mushrooms.
Huh?
"Taiwanese Vegetarianism."
Also known as "su-shi", it's a special cuisine
developed by certain monks in ancient times.
So it's something like shoujin cuisine?
Note: Shoujin Cuisine is a vegetarian cuisine developed by Buddhist Monks
Sort of.
The difference is that, unlike in shoujin, they
don't just cook materials in their raw form -
they manipulate stuff like beans and
mushrooms to simulate meat and fish.
Sort of like that sandwich you didn't finish eating.
Seriously?
But still...
why did monks in Taiwan come up
with such a tedious cooking method?
There's no need if they never knew
the taste of meat in the first place.
Well, yeah.
But see, everyone can eat what they want
before becoming a Buddhist priest.
Even though they may be training as
ascetics, they can't erase memories of their past.
I see.
Still, you're awfully knowledgeable about this.
Could it be that even you get
nostalgic about the taste of "real" food?
Even though I am a cyborg, my brain hungers for food.
My point is, that's why cyborg food is
made for entertainment purposes.
So, taste as a replay device that
permits us to recall memories of our past...
Where would Kawashima
have come across such cuisine?
He probably tried it out when he was stationed in Taiwan.
You guys, keep watching, okay?
Okey-dokey!
What now?
Well, tonight's theme is the refugee issue and terrorism,
and I'd like to organise the flow of the events until now,
but could it be summarised as the appearance of radical factors,
born of a directionless government's neglect
and the resulting rise of the particularists,
and who perceive restoration as being the answer to the problem?
That is incorrect. They did not appear because the current regime is weak.
Even before the current regime's inauguration,
defence-lobby lawmakers were thinking of concluding a new Japan-American Empire Security Treaty.
They thought then that they could take the initiative from the Empire.
Particularism therefore already existed parallel to these events.
Instead, what incited individualists towards violence are
the 3,000,000 refugees that are eating up our tax money.
It means it's about time this nation did something about them!
Place card: Dobashi
How interesting.
Then we shouldn't have accepted them in the first place.
Indeed. Not that it helps things.
However, do you know to what extent the Refugee Special Treatment Act has subjected the
people to tax increases since its implementation?
In addition, do you know that, using this policy as an excuse, these taxes...
Is anyone there?
Bring me the disc with the recording of the
debate programme that's currently airing on channel W3.
Understood.
And record the rest of the programme, of course.
Listen to me.
If you rapidly antagonise the refugees,
then they'll truly become uncontrollable.
Terrorism of the suicide bombing variety
is the last resort for them when they lose the last remaining ray of hope for their future.
That is why we must encourage the refugees to gain independence.
By giving them the freedom called "liberation."
What are you saying?!
How could the refugees solve their own problems, even if given freedom?!
Signs: Taiwanese Vegetarian Restaurant
Tachikoma, run a search on that vehicle's licence plate.
Roger!
Why don't we first present the full details of several acts of terrorism, then proceed to citing specific issues?
Place card: Dobashi Fumiya
This guy... he's the one I saw when..
Dobashi-San... what is this act of terrorism that the National
Police Agency is supposedly keeping hidden?
I'm pretty certain that you all know of the incidents at least,
but eight acts of terrorism have occurred following the Chinese Embassy's occupation, correct?
Are you referring to the incidents in which a cybernetic musician
and a Diet member, who had been advocating a reconciliation policy with the refugees, were stabbed to death?
That's correct.
It is a fact that the National Police Agency has released no information whatsoever regarding these cases to the media.
Stop showing off and tell us already.
Have you ever seen this symbol?
At first glance, it just seems to be a
normal vehicle registered to a retail chain.
I see.
This is a symbol that was inscribed on all the letters that had been sent as claims of responsibility.
I've never heard of this.
This man... Why does he know this? I've never heard of this.
This man... Why does he know this?
How's it going?
Are you letting the Tachikoma handle the stakeout?
Er, well...
That's not persuasive at all.
Here you go.
Hey, now's not the time to be eating stuff like that!
What? This is real.
Not about that; it's this guy.
I think he's one of the reporters
in a group I came across before,
but he knows classified information
about the Individual Eleven Case.
...but the people who're committing these crimes under this alias
are a group of people who have appeared individually, without any ties to one another, yet
they fall under a shared motive, refugee liberation.
What the hell is this guy saying?
These individualists began to appear after those GSDF helicopters flew around over the residential refugee sector.
These people genuinely mean to liberate the refugees...
So there are cases of infection like this as well...
Sign: Heated Debate! The Refugee Issue and Terrorism
Yes. We can't erode the police's dignity too much, so we thought he would be a
good "spark" to set things off.
True.
By the way, what about the infected who were involved in the
Nanyou case and the Prime Minister's attempted assassination?
Ah, yes.
Regarding the one involved in the Nanyou case,
we've already manipulated Public Safety Section 1,
so I believe we will be able to purge him soon enough.
As for the one involved in the Prime
Minister's attempted assassination,
we believe it is someone who was
deployed to the Peninsula as a PKF member.
His name is Kuze Hideo.
We arrived at this conclusion by tracking
backwards from the infectious agent,
so we probably have the right man.
Kuze-kun, eh?
About that man you asked about, Gouda:
even though I asked my former coworkers
at the Bureau of Defence Policy,
almost no one remembered anything about him.
And, even if they did remember him, they
only recalled him being rather unremarkable,
However, we did find records of the psychological testing
he'd received while being considered for employment.
"While introverted, subject possesses a strong
sense of self and exhibitionist tendencies.
On the other hand, subject displays a
tendency to use others in order to assert himself."
Somewhat different from how I
visualise his character to be today.
What's the matter? Aren't you going to eat?
The taste hasn't changed.
It hasn't, eh.
Oh, and about Kawashima, the SDF officer
you asked me about...
Section 1 made an inquiry about him, too.
They said that an assassin named Wong Chu Ren
had stolen Kawashima's face and was hiding in Chinatown,
and requested the data on his face.
Why didn't you tell me that first?!
But I thought you'd have been notified of this already.
Major!
Setting the Nanyou case aside,
it's strange that Section 1 is on the move.
Tell Batou and Togusa ASAP.
I've already told them.
Wong Chu Ren?
He's an international terrorist from Taiwan.
An assassination order has been issued from above,
but I haven't received any
information about him switching his face.
Either we are being set up,
or Section 1 is being set up...
Either way, the timing of it all is weird.
Tachikoma, secure the guys we
saw back in that car, just in case.
Batou-San, the target has
appeared in the back of the restaurant!
What the...
Dammit!
This country's too extravagant for refugees to live in,
and yet it's not wealthy enough to take them in.
Wong Chu Ren, correct?
Huh?
Keep 'em there!
Roger!
Put the gun down!
Kawashima!
Who the hell are you guys?!
Stay down!
I'm sorry!
The alley was too narrow for
me and I couldn't be his shield.
You're Section 1, aren't you?
And you guys are?
We're in the same business.
Take a good look at this face.
He hadn't made his face cybernetic yet.
In other words, this guy isn't Wong Chu Ren.
What is the meaning of this?
Section 1 had solid information on this guy.
You guys are with Motoko!
It means you guys were duped.
Just like us.
Finding out a galaxy
of planets and stars within me.
Listening to each of them
and singing the same silent melody.
I've never seen such beauty
in possibility...
No smack of doubt or fear.
(Wake up)
I hear a voice.
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
I see inside
(Our time is now)
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
All I need,
to make all this reality.
(it's inside)
The beauty within the shell.
(deep within the shell)
(within the shell)
(Wake up)
I hear a voice
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
(the time is now)
I see inside,
see the light now ever holding me.
(the time is now)
All the truth,
(All the truth)
to make all this reality,
it's inside
right here within the shell.